<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<contentitemdata.kenticocommunity.qandaquestionpage>
  <ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
    <GUID>3f8d2620-c772-4697-9817-61fdefc5dceb</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.contentitemcommondata</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>Breaking-permisison-inheritance-on-a-tree-node--551db60e-tx8z04td</CodeName>
      <GUID>dc1c8bce-a7c2-4f33-8598-246b56219cfc</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.contentitem</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
  <ContentItemDataGUID>91532b36-b1e2-430b-bf60-d71707b518ff</ContentItemDataGUID>
  <QAndAQuestionPageAcceptedAnswerDataGUID>57db9995-76bf-476e-8eea-b402c0ada877</QAndAQuestionPageAcceptedAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAQuestionPageAuthorMemberID>2</QAndAQuestionPageAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAQuestionPageContent>
<![CDATA[
**I have a question on page permission inheritance, it's long but bear with me:**\
\
Suppose I have 3 different user roles: A, B, and C.

\
All three roles have permission to access a website channel, but I need to limit Role C so they can only edit the section under the tree node `/C`.

To achieve this, I add Role C to the root node without granting any permissions other than the built-in display permission. This allows Role C to see the entire tree, but not to view or edit any specific nodes. Then, I navigate to `/C` and break inheritance to customize the permissions for C. Now, Role C can see and edit the `/C` folder and everything within it but nothing else.

This setup works fine, but it can start becoming problematic when we have multiple roles (e.g., 5 roles), each needing access to only specific sections of the website channel. In such cases, we end up with many sections where inheritance is broken, affecting permissions for all roles.

For example, if Roles A and B also have edit access to `/C` (which has broken inheritance), what happens if I later need to restrict Role A to only edit `/A`? I would have to manually go through the entire tree to locate nodes with broken inheritance where Role A might still have edit privileges. Similarly, if I need to remove Role C altogether, I can remove their access to the channel, preventing them from editing anything. However, the `/C` node would still have broken inheritance, which is unnecessary. Multiply this scenario by 5 roles, and it quickly becomes unmanageable.

The issues are compounded most severely when the target folders are nested deeper in the tree. A direct child of ROOT is less an issue of course.

**Question:**\
Is there a better way to achieve this? Based on the documentation, it doesn't seem like it, but I am curious if there are plans for updates to role/channel/page permissions in the future.
]]>
  </QAndAQuestionPageContent>
  <QAndAQuestionPageDateCreated>2024-11-09 02:38:57Z</QAndAQuestionPageDateCreated>
  <QAndAQuestionPageDateModified>2024-11-09 02:38:57Z</QAndAQuestionPageDateModified>
  <QAndAQuestionPageDiscussionType>
    <![CDATA[[{"Identifier":"c50e7dd3-2b8e-47b5-96ee-3f04ccfde8b6"}]]]>
  </QAndAQuestionPageDiscussionType>
  <QAndAQuestionPageTitle>Breaking permisison inheritance on a tree node.</QAndAQuestionPageTitle>
</contentitemdata.kenticocommunity.qandaquestionpage>