<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<contentitemdata.kenticocommunity.blogpostcontent>
  <BlogPostContentAuthor>
    <![CDATA[[{"Identifier":"03bc0324-27b7-44a5-b738-8835f4169db9"}]]]>
  </BlogPostContentAuthor>
  <BlogPostContentBlogType>
    <![CDATA[[{"Identifier":"23549e28-5004-4376-bfa0-074f16d1b1a9"}]]]>
  </BlogPostContentBlogType>
  <BlogPostContentContentMarkdown>
<![CDATA[
We are thrilled to announce an array of engaging and insightful events lined up in April and May for our community. From webinars delving into the intricacies of digital experience technology stacks to conferences aimed at fostering knowledge-sharing and networking, there's something for everyone. Let's take a closer look at what's in store.

## Webinar: Accelerating AllSeater's Website Development – Red Door Interactive's Swift Success with Xperience by Kentico

**Date & Time**: April 25, 2024 at 2:00pm EST

**Hosted By**: Kentico and Red Door Interactive

**Event Link**: [Accelerating AllSeater's Website Development](https://www.kentico.com/discover/webinars/accelerating-allseater-s-website-development-red-door-interactive-s-swift-success-with-xperience-by)

**Description**:

Dive into the journey of AllSeater's website development with Red Door Interactive and Xperience by Kentico. In this webinar, discover how leveraging the power of Kentico's Xperience platform enabled Red Door Interactive to achieve rapid and impactful results for AllSeater. Gain insights into best practices, innovative strategies, and real-world success stories that will inspire and empower your own projects.

**Speakers**: 
- Candice Wyatt, Sr. Dir., Web & Platform Solutions, Red Door Interactive
- Gary Peterson, CEO, AllSeater
- Mike Hennessey, Sr Customer Success Manager, Kentico

## 22nd Annual AMA BrandSmart Conference

**Date & Time**: April 25, 2024, 9-5:00pm

**Location**: Navy Pier Chicago

**Event Link**: [AMA BrandSmart Conference](https://www.kentico.com/discover/events/ama-brandsmart-conference)

**Description**:

Join us at the AMA BrandSmart Conference for a dynamic exchange of ideas, strategies, and insights in the field of marketing. This conference brings together industry leaders, innovators, and thought-provokers for engaging discussions, interactive sessions, and invaluable networking opportunities. Explore the latest trends, discover cutting-edge technologies, and connect with peers who share your passion for shaping the future of marketing. Visit our booth and learn more about how we can enhance your digital strategy. 

**Meet with**: 
- Wesley McChristian, Kentico Practice Director, Americaneagle.com
- Mark Fleischer, Channel Growth Director, Kentico

## Swaay Health Conference

**Date & Time**: May 6-9, 2024

**Location**: W Hotel, Atlanta GA

**Event Link**: [Swaay.Health Conference](https://healthitmarketingconference.com/)

**Description**:

Join Kentico and BizStream at the largest gathering of healthcare B2B and B2C marketers for a unique learning experience (formerly HITMC Annual Conference). Swaay.Health is a place for healthcare marketers from provider organizations, medical device makers, payers, and health IT companies.  BizStream will be presenting a case study on their recent website build for [Hospital Sisters Health System](https://www.kentico.com/discover/success-stories/hospital-sisters-health-system). 

**Meet with**: 
- Dean Mavrikos, Kentico
- Drew Veach, BizStream
- Rex Raney, BizStream

## Financial Brand Forum

**Date & Time**: May 20-23, 2024

**Location**: Aria Hotel, Las Vegas

**Description**:

Over 2500 senior executives at the biggest conference in marketing, CX, data analytics, AI, and digital growth strategies in the banking world.

### Demo Session

**Date & Time**: Tuesday May 21 at 10:30 

**Event Link**: [Demo Session](https://www.kentico.com/discover/events/financial-brand-forum-kentico-and-silvertech-demo)

**Description**:

Join Kentico and SilverTech for an interactive demo during the event. Sean Wright from Kentico will demo XbyK for the financial market and Christina Baker will talk about the number of financial institutions and credit union websites that they built. 

**Meet with**: 
- Sean Wright, Kentico
- Christina Baker, SilverTech

### Power Breakfast

**Date & Time**: Wednesday May 22 at 7:15-8:30am

**Event Link**: [Power Breakfast](https://www.kentico.com/discover/events/power-breakfast-at-financial-brand-forum)

**Description**:

Join Kentico, Americaneagle.com and First Service Credit Union for a fireside chat and enjoy breakfast. You will learn: How to get your executive team on board in regard to your digital goals; the ins and outs of what it takes to begin your web project; how to choose the best DX platform according to your needs, and more.

**Meet with**: 
- Sean Wright, Kentico
- Wes McChristian, Americaneagle.com
- Kerry Graham, First Service Credit Union

## Wrap Up

Stay tuned for more updates and details on these exciting events. Whether you're looking to enhance your digital strategy, gain inspiration for your projects, or expand your professional network, our upcoming events offer a wealth of opportunities to learn, grow, and connect!

Don't miss out—mark your calendars and reserve your spot today!
Visit [kentico.com/discover/events](https://www.kentico.com/discover/events) for more information!

]]>
  </BlogPostContentContentMarkdown>
  <BlogPostContentPublishedDate>2024-03-29 19:47:00Z</BlogPostContentPublishedDate>
  <BlogPostContentSourceType>markdown</BlogPostContentSourceType>
  <ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
    <GUID>e8852427-cf96-451f-966c-e0472de3d9c9</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.contentitemcommondata</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>KenticoCommunityEvents-Spring2024-qiagccnz</CodeName>
      <GUID>6e71b64d-f558-4911-a9c2-6c177e581b14</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.contentitem</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
  <ContentItemDataGUID>aa6edb62-3505-4ace-913d-b6ddb164a343</ContentItemDataGUID>
</contentitemdata.kenticocommunity.blogpostcontent>