<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<contentitemdata.kenticocommunity.blogpostcontent>
  <BlogPostContentAuthor>
    <![CDATA[[{"Identifier":"2dce9183-2830-4794-ad72-edd6bd9dc5c3"}]]]>
  </BlogPostContentAuthor>
  <BlogPostContentBlogType>
    <![CDATA[[{"Identifier":"0865e8f6-2568-425e-94d8-2bf53adcdd57"}]]]>
  </BlogPostContentBlogType>
  <BlogPostContentContentMarkdown>
<![CDATA[
Our [product roadmap for Xperience by Kentico](https://roadmap.kentico.com/tabs/6-next-refreshes) has been updated, detailing enhancements we plan to ship with our Refreshes for November and December of this year.

[![Xperience by Kentico roadmap - Next Refreshes](/getmedia/eba598e7-2904-4b41-b056-fa39203928bf/xperience-by-kentico-roadmap-202311.webp)](/getmedia/eba598e7-2904-4b41-b056-fa39203928bf/xperience-by-kentico-roadmap-202311.webp)

## Preset Page Templates

Preset Page Templates were temporarily disabled in the product with the v27.0.0 release so that we could improve them for our multichannel architecture. We're now re-enabling them as global objects, available for any website channel because Page Templates can also be reused across multiple channels.

## .NET 8

Microsoft will release the latest LTS version of .NET, .NET 8, during [.NET Conf this November 14-16](https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-conf-2023-celebrating-the-release-of-dotnet-8-save-the-date/).

We want to enable developers and customers to leverage all the greatness that comes with this new version of .NET, like the [amazing number of performance improvements](https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/performance-improvements-in-net-8/) that customers will see just by updating their projects from .NET 6 to .NET 8.

Free perf, yay 🤗!

## Improved Localized Content Creation

Today, creating a new localized variant of some content is easy to start through the UI (either Website Pages or reusable Content Items) but you have to author the new content without the context of the original. This update will let you populate the new localized content from the original to make translating easier.

## Cascading Content Publishing

When [modeling content for reusability](https://docs.xperience.io/x/f4HWCQ), marketers can end up with many smaller content items when compared to classic in-webpage content authoring. Often there can be a "parent" item that all other content items are related to. We will be enabling a "cascade" publish where marketers can publish the main item along with selected linked items that are in an unpublished state, improving their content management process.

## Integration with CRM

We are developing an open source starter kit that developers can use as a guide for custom CRM integrations with Xperience by Kentico. This project will include integrations for both Salesforce Sales Cloud and Microsoft Dynamics. This should accelerate developers' abilities to get these kinds of solutions designed and deployed.

## Headless Channels

With [v27.0.0 of Xperience by Kentico](https://docs.xperience.io/xp/changelog#Changelog-Refresh(October12,2023)) we enabled true website and email channel management. Our "headless API", which was in preview, has been taken back into the shop to make it production ready and incorporating the feedback we received from partners and customers.

With this update, marketers will be able to create headless channels themselves, model the content they want to expose through them, and then developers can consume that content for a variety of destinations - like mobile apps or external websites.

---

Are you excited for these enhancements to Xperience by Kentico? Want to see something else in the product that isn't on the roadmap? Let us know by [submitting an idea](https://roadmap.kentico.com/tabs/6-next-refreshes) on our roadmap site via the button in the top right of the page.











]]>
  </BlogPostContentContentMarkdown>
  <BlogPostContentDXTopics>
    <![CDATA[[{"Identifier":"57224794-f403-47a4-995c-7c748dbd6524"},{"Identifier":"53529b65-dba0-4617-a3bf-859b1bc25909"},{"Identifier":"9d7f9413-3142-4f27-a6bc-fb9ec266d45f"},{"Identifier":"1a2a8dca-bfab-4c00-ac5d-898d0a08d5e4"},{"Identifier":"c12240df-ec77-4517-8bbf-f372ea70b52d"}]]]>
  </BlogPostContentDXTopics>
  <BlogPostContentPublishedDate>2023-11-02 17:07:00Z</BlogPostContentPublishedDate>
  <BlogPostContentSourceType>markdown</BlogPostContentSourceType>
  <ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
    <GUID>d7174c82-00fd-4988-8aa1-d9fd45ea354c</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.contentitemcommondata</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>XperienceByKenticoProductRoadmapUpdates-Q42023-irayfzn0</CodeName>
      <GUID>81a251fa-99fa-468d-a73c-58047a327ae6</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.contentitem</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
  <ContentItemDataGUID>0060e137-3251-441f-9fe6-e4bd018226af</ContentItemDataGUID>
</contentitemdata.kenticocommunity.blogpostcontent>