<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<contentitemdata.kenticocommunity.qandaquestionpage>
  <ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
    <GUID>bb435a7a-5a2a-47ab-9bcb-10360e7483db</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.contentitemcommondata</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>Best-Practices-for-Managing-a-Common-Database-in-a-Centralized-Development-Setup-with-XByK--dc71vvvi</CodeName>
      <GUID>2d005598-9795-44c3-b983-2dc2b54bb550</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.contentitem</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
  <ContentItemDataGUID>1e4164a1-b7a8-426e-9c37-bfcb5cac9417</ContentItemDataGUID>
  <QAndAQuestionPageAcceptedAnswerDataGUID>b4fc0fa7-42b2-47f4-a593-ce3fd1fd4317</QAndAQuestionPageAcceptedAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAQuestionPageAuthorMemberID>4</QAndAQuestionPageAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAQuestionPageContent>
<![CDATA[
Hello **Kentico** Community,

We are using **Xperience by Kentico** in a centralized development environment and Git for version control. All developers in our team work with a shared database hosted on a common local server. While this setup simplifies collaboration to some extent, we are facing challenges with database management, such as:

1. Handling synchronization when multiple developers make updates to the database.
2. Managing schema changes without introducing conflicts or disruptions.
3. **Ensuring database integrity and consistency across different environments (local, staging, production).**

We’re seeking guidance on the **best practices** for managing a shared database in this context. Specifically, we’d like to know:

* How to efficiently synchronize database changes while using Git for code version control?
* Are there recommended tools, workflows, or techniques for managing schema changes and content staging in Xperience?
* Would it be better to move to an alternative setup for database management in a multi-developer environment?

Your insights, experiences, or recommendations would be highly appreciated.

Thank you in advance for your help!
]]>
  </QAndAQuestionPageContent>
  <QAndAQuestionPageDateCreated>2025-01-22 18:12:11Z</QAndAQuestionPageDateCreated>
  <QAndAQuestionPageDateModified>2025-01-22 18:12:11Z</QAndAQuestionPageDateModified>
  <QAndAQuestionPageDiscussionType>
    <![CDATA[[{"Identifier":"c50e7dd3-2b8e-47b5-96ee-3f04ccfde8b6"}]]]>
  </QAndAQuestionPageDiscussionType>
</contentitemdata.kenticocommunity.qandaquestionpage>