<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>f69d9d84-4ca9-4a3d-80f0-cff18438940a</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>-Ben-YAY-I-know-our-user-base-down-here-ina1ea8712</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent>
<![CDATA[
@Ben

> YAY!! I know our user base down here in Australia will be glad to see dates now in AUS format

We had an internal company debate about who has the best date/time format. It was mostly agreed that the U.S. format is not it!

> Also good to see that inactive contact deletion is now included in the product.

After running the Kentico Community Portal for several years with lots of anonymous visitors... so am I!

@Jeroen

> This is another fantastic leap forward and truly demonstrates how AI shines within a DXP. I can't wait to share this with our clients!

That AIRA application on the Xperience dashboard is quickly filling up with feature toggles and the AIRA translation improvements planned for September are the icing on the AIRA cake.

@Milan

> I’m looking forward to better image variants in the next one!

I know a lot of people are. [The planned image handling improvements](https://roadmap.kentico.com/c/344--improvement-usability-scalability-enhancements) were driven by partner and customer feedback after our recent digital asset features and we quickly prioritized them.

***

I had a lot of fun digging into [AIRA customer journey insights](https://community.kentico.com/blog/xperience-by-kentico-refresh-august-25-2025#aira-insights-for-customer-journeys) and generating data to help tell the story of this feature. I know a bit about how it all works behind the scenes and I'm very excited for the possibilities it opens up for AIRA in Xperience.
]]>
  </QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2025-08-29 03:14:37Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>84fd76d5-0d0c-4232-ae54-d917a85e754b</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Blog-Discussion-Xperience-by-Kentico-Refresh-August-25-2025-20a68441-anqwej1j</CodeName>
    <GUID>b9d33c73-c03a-449a-ad8f-dc7f683e46ce</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>