<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>b63e360d-4b76-4418-a8a7-affd51730462</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>-Danny-Paul-The-answer-to-this-question-is12f2fcf7</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent><![CDATA[
@Danny-Paul

The answer to this question is easiest to explain by looking at the other channel types.

If you want to expose a reusable content item over a website or email channel, can you just "expose it"?

Nope! You need to create a web page or email to deliver that reusable content item through in that channel. This is intentional.

Headless channels work the same way. You need to [create a headless item](https://docs.kentico.com/x/xIWOD) that exposes the reusable content.

Headless channels are not meant to be a tunnel into the database for developers. Instead, they are meant to give marketers complete control over what content is exposed through the channel.

All that said... yes, today headless channels are not flexible enough to expose a "set" of reusable content items and instead they much each be explicitly selected.

However, we have a planned way to resolve this issue. [Smart folders](https://roadmap.kentico.com/c/200-content-organization-discovery-smartfolders), which we will be delivering soon, will allow marketers to create dynamic sets of content and then select the smart folder as the source of related content for a headless item's related content field.

In the meantime, I recommend creating a [global event handler](https://docs.kentico.com/x/r4t1CQ) that updates a headless item's related content items every time a new article is published.

You might be able to find inspiration in the [Community Portal source code](https://github.com/Kentico/community-portal/blob/v28.4.0.2/src/Kentico.Community.Portal.Web/Features/Blog/Events/BlogPostPublishCreateQAndAQuestionHandler.cs) 👍.
]]></QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2024-03-30 03:22:55Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>6eb0007c-00fa-4221-8b8f-ee8107c3592b</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Retrieve-reusable-data-with-Headless-chan-9855b68e</CodeName>
    <GUID>a24e521d-1d4b-4b9e-a821-70b912a279d9</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>