<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>7577a98f-036d-454e-8e19-5ff0881e6fc7</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>-I-wouldn-t-expect-this-anytime-soon-but-t3de37c77</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent>
<![CDATA[
> I wouldn't expect this anytime soon, but the ability to embed references to Content Hub items/Structured Content within a rich text/markdown editor would be great, and then the channel that is responsible for displaying that content would replace that block with the appropriate rendering. But this isn't something I'd see as a baseline requirement.

This is basically the approach WordPress and some headless CMS products have taken.

I understand the appeal! But I've also seen how much the WordPress Gutenberg maintainers have worked to get a high quality experience out of it. It's a long road and the payoff seems... not huge, given the other drawbacks of rich text vs structured content.

I can still be convinced otherwise, but right now I feel that pulling content and metadata _out_ of rich text and managing it as separate structured information is a better approach than putting more structured information into rich text.

---

I agree with you that the basics need to work well - bold, italic, heading, URLs, lists, paragraphs. These need to all work intuitively with a really smooth UX.
]]>
  </QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2024-08-30 01:56:27Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>a12357aa-59a1-4cbd-b49e-9c916fcc0e00</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Blog-Discussion-How-important-are-rich-text-authoring-experiences-in-2024--e5546d48-3tzpwwig</CodeName>
    <GUID>756ec333-28eb-4a33-bc32-730041285a59</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>