<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>7577a98f-036d-454e-8e19-5ff0881e6fc7</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>-liamgold-there-are-still-scenarios-where-408d3954</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent><![CDATA[
@liamgold

> there are still scenarios where rich text is needed - like when text fields require more than plain text, such as hyperlinks.

Yep, this is the most common scenario I've seen along with lists along, bold, italic, and smaller headings (`<h1>` is always handled by a template or component).

> I prefer to minimise the functionality/toolbar options to only what's necessary.

Good strategy. Do you ever worry that content will be copied into a rich text editor from somewhere else and bring along styling that the toolbar wouldn't allow?

> I’d love to see a native Markdown editor alongside the rich text editor

I'm definitely biased, but I'd love to see one as well. 

I was thinking about these questions while writing the post.

- How important are improvements to rich text/markdown editing in Xperience by Kentico compared to all the other features?
- What's the baseline where improvements have diminishing returns?
- What we have today wouldn't be good enough for Kentico Portal Engine sites from 7 years ago, but what's that gap for what is needed today?

> I use the page builder to fully drive my blog post's content.

Good to know it's working for you! I definitely think I'm going to try it out, if only to improve my editing experience now that I'm storing media assets in the Content hub and want to reuse more existing content in blog posts.
]]></QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2024-08-29 16:06:34Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>9cc136f9-253c-4ab0-85ca-9951816c9abe</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Blog-Discussion-How-important-are-rich-text-authoring-experiences-in-2024--e5546d48-3tzpwwig</CodeName>
    <GUID>756ec333-28eb-4a33-bc32-730041285a59</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>