<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>7577a98f-036d-454e-8e19-5ff0881e6fc7</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>-seangwright-Good-strategy-Do-you-ever-wor1b61f3eb</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent><![CDATA[
@seangwright

> Good strategy. Do you ever worry that content will be copied into a rich text editor from somewhere else and bring along styling that the toolbar wouldn't allow?

I encourage our clients to use 'Paste as Plain Text' (Ctrl+Shift+V) to remove unwanted formatting and retain only the text content. This way, they can reapply formatting like bold, italics, and hyperlinks, ensuring the document remains clean and well-structured.

> How important are improvements to rich text/markdown editing in Xperience by Kentico compared to all the other features?

While adding new features to Xperience by Kentico is valuable, I believe it's crucial to focus on improving the core aspects of content entry, such as enhancing the rich text editor or integrating a proper Markdown editor. These tools are fundamental to our new projects, and clients often encounter issues with the current setup. For example, the internal page selector currently displays a long `cmsctx` preview URL instead of the actual selected page URL, which is not ideal for content editors and marketers. It causes confusion and can lead to delays in content actually being published.

> What's the baseline where improvements have diminishing returns?

I think the core functionality for rich text/markdown editor needs to be there, bold/italics/hyperlinks/headings. A proper baseline that is solid would be amazing, and then anything above any beyond that could be added in future releases.

I wouldn't expect this anytime soon, but the ability to embed references to Content Hub items/Structured Content within a rich text/markdown editor would be great, and then the channel that is responsible for displaying that content would replace that block with the appropriate rendering. But this isn't something I'd see as a baseline requirement.
]]></QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2024-08-29 18:26:33Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>863620fd-0cdf-4f19-a3e5-2e0ef061bb4b</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Blog-Discussion-How-important-are-rich-text-authoring-experiences-in-2024--e5546d48-3tzpwwig</CodeName>
    <GUID>756ec333-28eb-4a33-bc32-730041285a59</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>