<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>dc609851-ab9c-436c-9e99-5c5216d1560f</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>1-100-if-they-re-not-using-the-Page-Builde178e0038</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent>
<![CDATA[
1. 100% - if they're not using the Page Builder then they're losing out on a ton of the value of website channels (marketer control of the experience, personalization)\
   However, that doesn't mean _every page_ relies on the Page Builder!\
   Home page, landing pages, key product and service pages - these always use the Page Builder.\
   If you have 1,000 products you want to feature on a website these would not use the Page Builder. No marketing team can build those out using the Page Builder so instead you would use templates that predefine layouts and content based on some business rules.
2. Yes. But it's combined with the structured content fields of the web page and reusable content from the Content hub.
3. I've seen anywhere from 10 to 30, so 20 is probably a good average for larger projects. The number and functionality of widgets should have a great marketer experience as a goal and work within the constraints of the content model, website design variations, and brand/experience requirements.
4. Yes. This is how we market and message Xperience by Kentico - it puts marketers in control of the content, design, and brand of their digital channels. Technical teams set up the guardrails with the logic of components and Page Builder restrictions (as Milan mentioned), but marketers should be empowered to work confidently within those constraints.
5. The amount of logic and complexity you put into a widget (to handle more use cases and content) is a trade-off of developer experience and marketer experience.\
   When marketers use complex widgets there can be a frustrating learning curve, it can be difficult for developers to guarantee design and brand consistency, and evolving these widgets over time (as marketing strategy and requirements change) is difficult because you don't want regressions when deploying a change.\
   Really complex widgets also have the smell of engineers who want to over-complicate things 😅.\
   With Kentico Portal Engine people used Repeaters as the catch-all presentational component. I was not a fan. They were too complex and too many combinations of options led to poor or broken results.\
   Simple widgets that have a very clear purpose and are focused on a single content type can have plenty of benefits. There's a happy middle ground that's probably different for each Xperience project, dev team, and marketing team.
]]>
  </QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2025-08-20 17:12:30Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>8208afdb-bcec-4dba-b95a-bee1772c05e4</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Widget-Usage-Trends-in-Kentico-Page-Builder-3acdcee8-ug9klgkp</CodeName>
    <GUID>96c18786-8933-41c3-9301-02d1e548fce7</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>