<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>dc609851-ab9c-436c-9e99-5c5216d1560f</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>Brenden-Thanks-for-sharing-your-experienceee19ff46</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent>
<![CDATA[
Brenden,

Thanks for sharing your experiences and perspective!

It's sad to see [what happened with THAT Conference](https://thatconference.com/blog/that-conference-2025). I never attended but I always heard good things from the people that did.

COVID definitely had an impact on a lot, as did the end of the "become a developer in a bootcamp" hype cycle.

I find it interesting that video and social media tech content has also become competition against in-person events. I never attended conferences to watch sessions because they were often made public 3-6 months later. I did attend local meetups for the presentations because people would present on things outside my focus area and I could ask questions to get more insights. However, if pure knowledge was all I wanted, I would have stayed home and watched YouTube videos.

Why did I go out to local meetups and travel to conferences?

* Supporting speakers that I knew personally

* Hallway conversations

* Making new connections

* Participating in something that felt bigger than myself

* Recurring meetups and conferences became ways to stay in touch with newly made friends and get myself out of the house

I wonder how much of that people get today without in-person events 🤔. It seemed like those things were important to many in 2019. Something else changed, but I'm not sure what.
]]>
  </QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2025-08-15 01:14:38Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>98a6a8b7-1196-4666-941d-ad494d981f3d</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Are-any-of-you-attending-conferences-or-user-groups-over-the-past-few-years--623a76f0-0xd8awev</CodeName>
    <GUID>9e8ab741-64ff-4401-b257-b837194b850b</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>