<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>7577a98f-036d-454e-8e19-5ff0881e6fc7</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>Great-read-Sean-I-believe-rich-text-authoraf04d5de</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent>
<![CDATA[
Great read, Sean!

I believe rich text authoring remains important, but its role has evolved. In the past, rich text was often overused, giving marketers and content editors near-total control over page content. Nowadays, even with structured content, there are still scenarios where rich text is needed - like when text fields require more than plain text, such as hyperlinks. When I use rich text in projects, I prefer to minimise the functionality/toolbar options to only what's necessary. 😂

In these cases, a Markdown editor could be a great alternative. It allows editors to manage text while easily inserting hyperlinks. For Xperience by Kentico projects, I’d love to see a native Markdown editor alongside the rich text editor - one that's user-friendly and includes the Kentico internal/external URL selector.

On [my blog website](https://www.goldfinch.me/), I use the page builder to fully drive my blog post's content. For text, I rely on the rich text widget (mainly for the internal/external URL selector). However, I often add images or videos between text blocks using structured content from the content hub, through Image/Video widgets. These widgets retrieve the image or video, along with descriptions and any other metadata stored for those assets. This approach gives me, as a developer, full control over the visual display of these elements. It also ensures editors don’t place images or videos inside rich text widgets, maintaining consistency and flexibility in content layout.
]]>
  </QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2024-08-29 02:57:11Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>1cb1d95b-8790-4306-95f3-58eb0e4a8b2a</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Blog-Discussion-How-important-are-rich-text-authoring-experiences-in-2024--e5546d48-3tzpwwig</CodeName>
    <GUID>756ec333-28eb-4a33-bc32-730041285a59</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>