<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>8fb0dad6-8c28-43e4-849b-684df65417a7</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>I-don-t-think-there-is-another-way-to-solvb146649f</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent>
<![CDATA[
I don't think there is another way to solve your challenge. I'm not sure how the UX of the tree permissions would work for this situation - you want to override (break) permissions but also have them keep inheriting to make managing them easier 🤔.

I don't think there are plans to enhance the ACL functionality of website channel page trees in the near future.

We will be delivering Content hub workspaces in December's Refresh. This will enable you to segment the Content hub into discrete collections of content (workspaces) and assign roles to the View/Edit/Update permissions for all the content in each workspace. Potentially moving some page content into Content hub workspaces _could_ help.

I would also recommend looking at [custom Workflows](https://docs.kentico.com/x/workflows_xp) to limit the impact a marketer can have on pages. Workflows are configured for content types but they are another tool to limit publishing updates of pages.

We'll be delivering administration Notifications in an upcoming Refresh so marketers can be easily notified via email when a content item (or web page) is in a workflow step that they are authorized to approve.
]]>
  </QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2024-11-09 03:33:50Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>57db9995-76bf-476e-8eea-b402c0ada877</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Breaking-permisison-inheritance-on-a-tree-node--551db60e-tx8z04td</CodeName>
    <GUID>1e6379a3-7cd7-4c84-a6bf-684a730d1738</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>