<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>dc609851-ab9c-436c-9e99-5c5216d1560f</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>I-think-I-might-agree-with-you-though-I-ca434998c2</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent>
<![CDATA[
I think I might agree with you, though I can also see how it depends on your goals.

I haven't used Cursor much but I've watched a lot of videos of developers using it. It's impressive and encourages more of a hands-off-the-code approach to software development - something closer to vibe coding even if you're still encouraged to review changes and re-prompt.

VS Code's Copilot features have been improving pretty quickly and fits the Copilot as-a-pair-programmer agentic AI development mindset. You're still in the drivers seat, have all the extensions and tools that help you write correct code quickly and confidently, while AI becomes one of those tools without replacing them.

I'll be publishing a blog post soon about my personal experiences using VS Code and the GitHub Copilot extension when working on the Kentico Community Portal. I've had some really positive experiences and I am definitely writing _less_ code, even if I haven't moved into the no-human-written code world.

I'm trying to keep an open mind because I used VS for years, then VS for backend and VS Code for front-end... finally, once I stopped working on KX13 projects I switched 100% to VS Code. It's a good reminder that tools change and getting too attached to one can prevent you from real productivity improvements.
]]>
  </QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2025-07-01 18:22:48Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>625cf572-7e20-469d-89b8-19d46824cc7a</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Blog-Discussion-Evolving-Dancing-Goat-with-agentic-AI-software-development-45873b7f-2edr5pzd</CodeName>
    <GUID>4f7cfddc-fbe9-40ba-b0db-ea1f3d09b8d5</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>