<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>b63e360d-4b76-4418-a8a7-affd51730462</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>I-will-throw-my-agency-experience-in-as-wea85df402</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent>
<![CDATA[
I will throw my agency experience in as well.

1. 100%. We haven't done a Kentico build in many years that didn't leverage widgets as the primary form of content management. While it doesn't apply to every page, it is almost always a vast majority of pages that leverage widgets through the PageBuilder for content.
2. Yes. While I don't sit right at the front of the sales pipeline, it's definitely an expectation by the time it reaches my hands in the discovery process.
3. We try and get it to 10-20 during the original build process. We find that post build though as additional widgets get added that this number can easily end up as 30+ on some projects. To add to this, we have also had a client request 30 widgets to replace their existing widget stack so they could effectively redesign their content progressively over time. We were able to introduce the new style widgets and when they were finished with their content migration, we simply retired and removed the legacy style widgets.
4. Definitely with our client base. We often have clients who have previously worked with Kentico or have already been through a review process prior to reaching out where they have seen and had a demo of Kentico. By the time we are talking to our clients, widgets and page builder are an expectation with their potential Kentico build.
5. We typically have a core set of content-based widgets that are fairly common to most of our builds and then extend that with a series of widgets that match our clients' specific requirements. Often, when planning our widgets we take a look at the editing experience specifically and plan our widgets around what provides the best experience for the content editors. With several sites containing well over 10,000 pages of content, it's worth making the widgets clear and easy to use.
]]>
  </QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2025-08-21 10:49:58Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>38860e25-09cc-4753-9201-4ddc753fef0d</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Widget-Usage-Trends-in-Kentico-Page-Builder-3acdcee8-ug9klgkp</CodeName>
    <GUID>96c18786-8933-41c3-9301-02d1e548fce7</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>