<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>7577a98f-036d-454e-8e19-5ff0881e6fc7</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>In-my-opinion-the-Page-Builder-experience-1a1c425e</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent>
<![CDATA[
In my opinion, the Page Builder experience is very attractive to customers and one of the main reasons they choose Kentico.

1. 90%+
2. From what I’ve heard from my clients, Kentico sales representatives present Page Builder when pitching Kentico and set the expectation that this is the default way of working. So, yes.
3. It varies based on site complexity. I always try to keep the number as low as possible while balancing usability and manageability. Still, in my case it’s usually 20+ widgets per website. I also try to limit which widgets are allowed in specific widget zones, depending on the context of use.
4. It’s a bit difficult to judge. From what I see, it’s beneficial for editors and marketers to have a visual guide, where Page Builder clearly helps. Especially compared to working with structured content in Content Hub.
5. I try to find a middle ground. As I mentioned, I balance ease of use (which is related to the number of widget properties and how much functionality a single widget provides) with the overall number of widgets.
]]>
  </QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2025-08-20 16:21:56Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>53a2a05f-3dd7-47c9-958d-758c0b34d34f</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Widget-Usage-Trends-in-Kentico-Page-Builder-3acdcee8-ug9klgkp</CodeName>
    <GUID>96c18786-8933-41c3-9301-02d1e548fce7</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>