<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>b63e360d-4b76-4418-a8a7-affd51730462</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>Liam-it-gives-clients-still-on-KX13-or-ear9c95d5db</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent>
<![CDATA[
Liam,

> it gives clients still on KX13 (or earlier) with commerce a clear path for migrating in the future ✅

That's one of our goals with digital commerce. We also know that commerce capabilities are an important dimension of DXP products and want to offer our marketing customers the features that will help them drive revenue. Commerce is an obvious piece to that puzzle!

Vasu,

> congrats on moving digital commerce to production-ready status — subscription support sounds like a huge win for B2B SaaS customers

Thanks! We're proud of the progress we've made over the past few Refreshes and we plan deliver new digital commerce features through the end of the year. Subscription support is just another one of those features we know will impact our partners and customers positively, and be a clear reason to upgrade from earlier versions of Kentico.

> Is there an ETA for date/time localization?

[We're planning date and time localization support in August](https://roadmap.kentico.com/c/334-basic-localization-support-for-admin-ui-date-time-formats). Numbers and currency shouldn't be too far behind either.
]]>
  </QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2025-07-30 17:47:49Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>a4d8bc4e-18f0-4df7-a884-14626f806fb3</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Blog-Discussion-Xperience-by-Kentico-Refresh-July-24-2025-90aea261-4k3m7h1n</CodeName>
    <GUID>df32da65-a05f-4866-840c-e82832125039</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>