<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>7577a98f-036d-454e-8e19-5ff0881e6fc7</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>Michael-we-also-like-to-periodically-zoom-655905be</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent><![CDATA[
Michael,

> we also like to periodically "zoom out" as a team and revisit our client’s vision, purpose, and online goals. This allows us to continuously guide and advise them in the right direction, ensuring that we're always aligned with their evolving needs.

Oh, this is a great point! I've seen those client priorities and goals pivot halfway through a project 😲. That's ok, especially if it is beneficial to the stakeholder to change focus, but the implementation team needs to discuss and document the change and evaluate what impact it will have on the project.

Being too flexible (just doing what the client requests) without communicating the impact of decisions leads to projects that at best miss expectations and at worst completely fail.

> we’ve started moving away from using JIRA for storing stories and specifications. Instead, we're increasingly using Confluence for this purpose.

It's great you mention this - adjusting your use of tools as you learn how to use them to produce the best outcomes for clients.

Should all teams make the same choice as your team? No... but, they should spend some time to identify opportunities to improve.
]]></QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2024-11-07 21:28:52Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>955848fc-817c-470c-ba8f-06ca745d7c38</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Blog-Discussion-Re-post-Key-Practices-for-Successful-Project-Management-db53084a-yoem5kl6</CodeName>
    <GUID>66ec2ed6-e76f-4c8f-9523-92fee887f7b9</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>