<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>b63e360d-4b76-4418-a8a7-affd51730462</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>Milan-is-correct-Image-transformation-in-Xd9a127e5</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent>
<![CDATA[
Milan is correct 👍.

Image transformation in Xperience by Kentico is currently performed **on upload**, which is different than previous versions of Kentico where the built-in image optimization was performed **on request**.

An additional explanation of the feature can be found in the Kentico Community blog post - [Xperience by Kentico Refresh - December 12, 2024](https://community.kentico.com/blog/xperience-by-kentico-refresh-december-12-2024#1-click-image-optimization).

This means you don't need to add [a hash/signature to every auto-generated image variant](https://docs.kentico.com/developers-and-admins/configuration/media-library-configuration#image-file-request-protection) to prevent a DoS attack of your application.

We only support 1 image variant at this time, but we plan to support multiple in the future and potentially offer a combination of **on upload** and **on request** optimization and transformation.

The original uploaded image is *always saved* (this lets you re-transform the original image after uploading) and if you download the image from the administration UI you are downloading the original un-transformed version. When retrieving the image via content delivery APIs, we always serve the transformed version of the image and you *do not* have direct access to the original through these APIs.

[Webp has much better support across email clients](https://www.caniemail.com/features/image-webp/) than it did even a few years ago, however if email recipients are not using the web or new desktop version of Outlook, they could have issues seeing the image.

If you want to avoid sending webp images to your email recipients today you would either need to specify a fallback image and [use VML](https://www.badsender.com/en/2024/04/16/outlook-email-display-problems/#h-le-vml) to render that only for older versions of Outlook.

That fallback image could be static or it could be a second Content Item Asset field on your Content Type that is configured to have optimization/transformation convert to a supported format like jpg or png.

If you would like to have more flexible image variant selection, [send us some feedback on our roadma](https://roadmap.kentico.com/tabs/6-next-refreshes)p explaining your use cases 👍.
]]>
  </QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2025-01-24 19:57:28Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>89c5e243-7f35-49d9-886b-cdb26ebf1e0f</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Question-regarding-automatic-image-file-type-conversion-2124c789-5y5otjut</CodeName>
    <GUID>7d6bbba9-ca4a-4cf0-83d1-26c561d841a7</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>