<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>7577a98f-036d-454e-8e19-5ff0881e6fc7</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>Nowadays-it-s-pretty-hard-to-judge-which-tfb9d1b71</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent>
<![CDATA[
Nowadays, it’s pretty hard to judge which tool is the best, since all of them are developing rapidly, competing with each other, and new ones keep popping up all the time. It also depends a lot on your workflow, projects, and expectations.

From my experience, I worked on a migration project (KX13 → XbyK) where I needed to migrate sections, widgets, and so on, often with some modifications. In my head, I just wanted to say, *“Migrate the ABC widget and make XYZ modifications.”*

I was really struggling with VS Code + Copilot (Visual Studio isn’t even worth mentioning, haha), because I couldn’t get it to have both the old and the new solutions in context. So I kept switching between them like a fool, copying files back and forth.

Then I heard great feedback about Cursor, gave it a try, and what a miracle. I could add both solutions into a single workspace, and everything was available in the context. And boom, I was able to migrate the features exactly the way I described above. It was a huge productivity booster, and I never looked back.

At the time, VS Code couldn’t do that, but reading the docs now, it looks like it has caught up. Will I go back to VS Code? It’s hard to predict. But never say never. Cursor isn’t all rainbows and unicorns either (yeah, I’m talking about the pricing and transparency around rate limits).
]]>
  </QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2025-07-05 00:07:54Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>7af6d993-5d4b-45b7-9f1a-33cb76f16612</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Blog-Discussion-Evolving-Dancing-Goat-with-agentic-AI-software-development-45873b7f-2edr5pzd</CodeName>
    <GUID>4f7cfddc-fbe9-40ba-b0db-ea1f3d09b8d5</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>