<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>7577a98f-036d-454e-8e19-5ff0881e6fc7</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>Prior-to-COVID-I-d-attend-about-5-per-yearb6f4eb1b</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent>
<![CDATA[
Prior to COVID I'd attend about 5 per year.  Out of those 5, 3 of them were Kentico related in one way shape or form.  The other 2 were more coding/technical related and business related.&#x20;



The Kentico User groups I attended were often 3 hours or so away driving.  Not a big issue really, however, if the user group is only an hour or two long, I now question the value of the content and my role attending the user group.  If someone asks me to present a topic, I'll 100% be there.  If I'm just attending, then I'll look at the content and value it adds to me and the company and then make a decision.&#x20;



My favorite conference I attended about an hour from me in Wisconsin Dells, WI was [THAT Conference](https://thatconference.com/). It's a pretty unique conference that I know many Kentico Partners in the area have attended and spoken at.  However, last year was the last event they had and don't anticipate to have any in the near future. &#x20;



We had a meetup in for .NET about 25 minutes from me.  I attended about a half dozen times, and it ended up just being 8 guys who worked at 2 different companies trying to get each other to do their work.  They stil meet, I don't go.  There was a Kentico user group in Green Bay and/or Milwaukee and Minneapolis, but not much activity with those two either. &#x20;



Now there are literally no meetups within 2 hours of me that have any attendance. Like Milan said, there's so much great content online these days, from tech influencers to recorded sessions, that I often feel I have what I need. From a comradery standpoint, nothing beats meeting your friends and peers in person though.  That alone is one great reason I'll spend money on a meeting, conference, meetup, etc.&#x20;
]]>
  </QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2025-08-14 19:41:29Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>1cdbf8f4-18e6-41bb-b2e7-09ffe78e0b33</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Are-any-of-you-attending-conferences-or-user-groups-over-the-past-few-years--623a76f0-0xd8awev</CodeName>
    <GUID>9e8ab741-64ff-4401-b257-b837194b850b</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>