<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>b63e360d-4b76-4418-a8a7-affd51730462</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>Rahul-While-the-official-kickstarter-may-b04006007</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent>
<![CDATA[
Rahul,

While the official kickstarter may be official, it can be somewhat far from a real "starting point" site.

You may want to check out the Xperience by Kentico Baseline project, this is the open source community turn-key solution that includes pretty much every core thing you need for a website, all set to go.  You can reach out to me if you want me to show you around, i'm still working on documentation, but installation is pretty easy!

[KenticoDevTrev/XperienceCommunity.Baseline: Core Systems, Tools, and Structure to ensure a superior Kentico Website that's easy to migrate, for Kentico Xperience 13 and Xperience by Kentico](https://github.com/KenticoDevTrev/XperienceCommunity.Baseline)



In it, there is a Navigation module, that gives you a Navigation Page Type that comes complete with:

1. Mega Menu (Widget) support
2. Automatic Navigation (Select the web page and it will handle the rest)
3. Manual Navigation (enter text, link, etc)
4. Dynamic Navigation (an entry point that you can customize and generate your own Navigation Items for it's children)



All you really need to do is overwrite a couple views with however the navigation HTML is structured for your template.



This is just one of the many features of the Baseline.
]]>
  </QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2025-01-03 00:44:25Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>b5d48829-5b02-4fc7-ae14-571ba9a473f2</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Navigation-Implementation-INavigation-vs-Repository-and-Kentico-Tag-Helper-2bb070a8-hv5masoy</CodeName>
    <GUID>a4756ff7-36e1-4180-b9d2-4733f301e1e2</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>