<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>b63e360d-4b76-4418-a8a7-affd51730462</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>Rich-Text-editing-is-a-crucial-feature-and29c65930</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent>
<![CDATA[
Rich Text editing is a crucial feature, and content editors appreciate the flexibility it provides for designing content with markup. However, as a developer, I always ensure that editors have only the functions they need, which varies based on the project, the editorial team, and their workflow.

It's important to understand that content created in Rich Text Editors is typically confined to the page where it's placed, making it inaccessible to other areas. If content needs to be reused elsewhere, it should be moved to a shared/structured location. Communicating this concept to content editors is one of my main responsibilities when consulting and training.

Even when there's no immediate need to share content across channels, using a structured approach can often be a better solution for the editing team. Rich Text editing can become cumbersome, especially when trying to create complex elements like accordions, FAQs, carousels, content tabs, or tables. Relying too heavily on these editors can lead to disorganized content and a poor editing experience.

Before implementing these complex components directly in Rich Text, consider moving them to structured data sources instead of creating confusing inline editors. From my experience, most of these elements benefit from being centralized, as they often need to be shared across multiple pages or platforms.

Platforms like Kentico offer robust alternatives to Rich Text editing for implementing such features, providing a more organized and maintainable approach.
]]>
  </QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2024-09-10 11:54:30Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>285f0f10-cae6-4e9f-a5c0-27454fc1d870</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Blog-Discussion-How-important-are-rich-text-authoring-experiences-in-2024--e5546d48-3tzpwwig</CodeName>
    <GUID>756ec333-28eb-4a33-bc32-730041285a59</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>