<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>7577a98f-036d-454e-8e19-5ff0881e6fc7</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>Some-great-improvements-here-and-the-rapidff177f04</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent>
<![CDATA[
Some great improvements here, and the rapid adoption of .NET 8 is unbelievably fast!

The language variant copying sounds good - I think similar functionality for when you duplicate a content item would be amazing. E.g. duplicate an existing content item or web page, you could control if it just copies the current language variant, specific language variants, or all language variants.

It's nice to see the rich text editor getting some improvements too. This did make me think of a scenario where you might want to embed references to content from the Content Hub (I'm thinking of how some Headless CMS work!), is this possible yet or in the future?

Example could be...a Blog Post on a website. The content type has a field for rich text to be entered by the content editor called 'Body'. This field needs to have Video, Image, Code Snippet, or some other piece of reusable structured content from the Content Hub injected inline between paragraphs. The developer would replace the reference with a view component or something to render the appropriate HTML inline.

If this isn't possible, what would the content modelling recommendation be here? I am probably answering my own question here, but I can probably take a look at the community site content models blog posts and how it constructs the page 🤔
]]>
  </QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2023-11-18 15:54:51Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>627c9515-e562-4cad-990d-b39b82485619</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Blog-Discussion-Xperience-by-Kentico-Refr-448d25b0</CodeName>
    <GUID>bef326f0-3064-4c0a-b4d2-f67d51f05526</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>