<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>
  <QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
    <GUID>c1beb8f9-4673-40d8-acdd-2dd56e5cd1bb</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.member</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>What-s-Ecomail-I-only-have-experience-with04930e6e</QAndAAnswerDataCodeName>
  <QAndAAnswerDataContent>
<![CDATA[
What's Ecomail? I only have experience with MailChimp and Constant Contact. I still use MailChimp to this day (for a personal business).

I think email channels and the Email Builder are much more advanced than these products in some ways, and less advanced in others.

List management, subscriber scoring, and list segmentation more advanced in the dedicated products, but [list segmentation](https://roadmap.kentico.com/c/321-enhanced-recipient-targeting-for-emails) is on Xperience's roadmap and [our planned unified contact profile improvement](https://roadmap.kentico.com/c/230-unified-contact-profile) leads the way for better customer data management.

The dedicated products also have multivariate email testing and some classic small but friendly features like "view this email as a web page" which Xperience doesn't have at the moment.

Where Xperience excels is anything related to content, messaging, and branding.

The drag and drop tools of email services are great for creating simple emails quickly, but the design customization features are very limiting for teams with clear brand requirements.

I've always copied and pasted content, exported and imported images, and had to do robust link checking with every email service I've used. That's because they have no real concept of content management or reuse.

Xperience's multichannel design + Email Builder functionality means my emails can match my brand and design requirements, and reusing content and linking to web pages requires *exactly 0 copy and paste*s. This means the risk of incorrect images, broken links, or mismatched description snippets is basically non-existent.

Also, from the commercial perspective, the email services scale in pricing with subscribers, emails sent, or advanced tools. It's roughly consumption based. Xperience by Kentico's email channels are a fixed cost which means a growing subscriber base or number of emails won't impact the cost and features like AIRA for content transformation, the Email Builder, multichannel content usage tracking, and subscriber activity tracking all come included.

We have some areas to improve for email marketing, but the foundation is really solid and absolutely usable today.
]]>
  </QAndAAnswerDataContent>
  <QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>2025-08-15 01:32:10Z</QAndAAnswerDataDateCreated>
  <QAndAAnswerDataGUID>0295dd4a-e096-4a52-97a2-9f6a6d4c29da</QAndAAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
    <CodeName>Blog-Discussion-Supercharge-Your-Email-Marketing-Essential-Email-Builder-Resources-for-Deve-mua9smv9</CodeName>
    <GUID>662ff399-d313-4b6b-8951-abf0c4295f88</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.webpageitem</ObjectType>
  </QAndAAnswerDataQuestionWebPageItemID>
  <QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
    <GUID>9ca57e0f-969f-43be-91d3-6c45659316bd</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.websitechannel</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>devnet</CodeName>
      <GUID>4f636110-fd4a-4905-83e6-998752c2b2c2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.channel</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </QAndAAnswerDataWebsiteChannelID>
</kenticocommunity.qandaanswerdata>