<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<contentitemdata.kenticocommunity.qandaquestionpage>
  <ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
    <GUID>8f901aac-521b-48f8-848d-9fbf2303fb9a</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.contentitemcommondata</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>Is-there-a-way-to-extend-the-AIRA-information-with-channel-framework-relatedauthoring-instr-flv05be0</CodeName>
      <GUID>a844dccf-6a3b-4fed-a7e6-c595847022fe</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.contentitem</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
  <ContentItemDataGUID>31984a64-34e7-40a7-a886-92d5050d8248</ContentItemDataGUID>
  <QAndAQuestionPageAcceptedAnswerDataGUID>b60f01b2-25d2-4a7c-a460-2923330bd7bd</QAndAQuestionPageAcceptedAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAQuestionPageAuthorMemberID>4</QAndAQuestionPageAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAQuestionPageContent>
<![CDATA[
Hi There,

We are just starting to play with AIRA, thanks for making it available in our accelerator environment.

I am loving the correctness of the AIRA helper and the outlinks to the Kentico Docs. As implementers I am finding it very helpful when I hit something that isnt configured.

What we find is that most of the informaiton that authors need on a day to day basis is specific to the framework we have put in place. i.e. how to use the page builder features we have built, which template do I chose, what to enter and when into the data fields in the content tab, even to how the check in check out workflow works.&#x20;

Is there a way that we can extend the information available from the Kentico Docs to provide instance level information. I.e. how to use the email marketing widgets that we have added, how to use the custom form fields we have developed, how to configure the backgroudn colour on one section within a 3 column section.

I provide this information by training, but it will feel wierd to authors if they cant ask the AI about that too.

***

**Environment**

* Xperience by Kentico version: 30.6.1

* .NET version: \[8]

* Execution environment: Private cloud&#x20;

*
]]>
  </QAndAQuestionPageContent>
  <QAndAQuestionPageDateCreated>2025-07-03 03:05:48Z</QAndAQuestionPageDateCreated>
  <QAndAQuestionPageDateModified>2025-07-07 20:26:55Z</QAndAQuestionPageDateModified>
  <QAndAQuestionPageDiscussionType>
    <![CDATA[[{"Identifier":"c50e7dd3-2b8e-47b5-96ee-3f04ccfde8b6"}]]]>
  </QAndAQuestionPageDiscussionType>
</contentitemdata.kenticocommunity.qandaquestionpage>