<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<contentitemdata.kenticocommunity.qandaquestionpage>
  <ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
    <GUID>2528d11e-ed79-4e73-92a2-2504e1bf53d4</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.contentitemcommondata</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>Is-DevOps-Still-One-of-the-Best-Career-Paths-in-Tech-Let-s-Discuss-0e2fd9fe-ucg04g9m</CodeName>
      <GUID>fd8863ad-b2d1-43b3-a8bd-0b160864a503</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.contentitem</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
  <ContentItemDataGUID>bf847291-f78a-49dc-8951-a307250912cf</ContentItemDataGUID>
  <QAndAQuestionPageAcceptedAnswerDataGUID>00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000</QAndAQuestionPageAcceptedAnswerDataGUID>
  <QAndAQuestionPageAuthorMemberID>1</QAndAQuestionPageAuthorMemberID>
  <QAndAQuestionPageContent>
<![CDATA[
Hello everyone,

With all the ongoing transformation in the Tech Industry-AI, cloud, automation-I have been pondering whether DevOps is still a great career path? In my opinion, the demand for DevOps is at a consistent growth stage, and companies rely on DevOps Engineers to deliver requests quicker, enable collaboration, and provide stable infrastructure implicitly.

What I like most about DevOps is that it is not a set of tools, it is a mindset; it removes the silos between development and operations and embraces automation, monitoring, and most importantly, delivers value to customers quicker.

This is where I have some conflicting feelings - DevOps feels extremely broad, CI/CD, Docker, Kubernetes, Scripting, Cloud Platforms, Monitoring Tools, etc. How do you manage to concentrate and plan a clearly defined learning path for someone starting out or someone learning to specialize?

Recently, I found several structured programs, which could be great for beginners and even those with IT experience looking to specialize:

This [DevOps Course in Pune](https://www.sevenmentor.com/devops-training-in-pune.php) is very thorough covering hands-on skills containerization, continuous integration and real use cases.

If you're trying to develop a good pipeline and toolchain knowledge, this DevOps Automation Course might be a good option.

And if you're looking to get into the field with mentors and projects to help, the DevOps Training in Pune program appears to offer great support.

So my question for all of you is:

Is DevOps still a top tech career choice going forward?

👉 How do you advise someone to get into the DevOps space in 2025 and beyond?

👉 Which area of DevOps do you believe has the most value to specialize in right now—cloud, automation, or monitoring?
]]>
  </QAndAQuestionPageContent>
  <QAndAQuestionPageDateCreated>2025-06-03 11:08:22Z</QAndAQuestionPageDateCreated>
  <QAndAQuestionPageDateModified>2025-06-03 11:08:22Z</QAndAQuestionPageDateModified>
  <QAndAQuestionPageDiscussionType>
    <![CDATA[[{"Identifier":"c50e7dd3-2b8e-47b5-96ee-3f04ccfde8b6"}]]]>
  </QAndAQuestionPageDiscussionType>
</contentitemdata.kenticocommunity.qandaquestionpage>