<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<contentitemdata.kenticocommunity.blogpostcontent>
  <BlogPostContentAuthor>
    <![CDATA[[{"Identifier":"edb67900-c7f5-4582-8c61-499f33c60785"}]]]>
  </BlogPostContentAuthor>
  <BlogPostContentBlogType>
    <![CDATA[[{"Identifier":"0865e8f6-2568-425e-94d8-2bf53adcdd57"}]]]>
  </BlogPostContentBlogType>
  <BlogPostContentContentMarkdown>
<![CDATA[
We are releasing the new Xperience by Kentico Certified Developer Exam to challenge and validate your skills.

Are you ready to see if you are up to speed with the latest Xperience by Kentico DXP? Do you want to prove your expertise and stand out in the Kentico developer community?

Boost your career credentials and take the [Xperience by Kentico certified developer exam](https://www.kentico.com/services/certification/xperience-developer-certification).

## Evergreen Xperience by Kentico, evergreen developer exam

The new Xperience by Kentico certification is not just another Kentico developer exam. [Xperience by Kentico](https://www.kentico.com/platforms/xperience-by-kentico) marked a significant milestone in Kentico 20-year history. It is a version-less, evergreen digital xperience platform with a public roadmap and monthly refreshes. It is built with modern technologies, like [ASP.NET  Core and React](https://www.kentico.com/platforms/xperience-by-kentico/development).

And the new developer exam reflects the core nature of the product.

Your certificate will be valid for two years. As Xperience by Kentico grows, we will keep updating the question bank to ensure that whoever passes the exam is a true expert who is up-to-speed with the latest features and recommended practices.

## Exam Success = Hands-on experience + Theoretical knowledge + Custom development skills 

We prepared the exam to distinguish developers who are not only familiar with but proficient at Xperience by Kentico. You'll need more than a cursory understanding of the solution to stand a chance at passing.

The exam demands a solid theoretical background, practical experience, and a deep dive into features and functionalities that you would typically use while designing, developing, and maintaining Xperience applications.

You are also expected to grasp ASP.NET  development, .NET Framework intricacies, MS SQL database management, and creating data-driven user interfaces. While our training materials are a starting point, we strongly recommend completing a project on Xperience by Kentico to improve your changes. Download the exam [Preparation guide](https://asset.cloudinary.com/xperience-io/6f56c1dcdeea2665957dcd2fe2f2ce07) and see which areas, topics, and resources we think you should master before attempting the exam.

## 50 questions in 75 minutes

The format of the exam remains similar to that of previous years. It consists of 50 single-answer questions to be completed within 75 minutes, covering extensive areas like Xperience content modeling, working with API, customizations, or integrations. You can still use resources such as [product documentation](https://docs.kentico.com/) and run Xperience by Kentico [locally](https://docs.kentico.com/guides/development/get-started/install-xperience-by-kentico) during the exam. However, it's important to note that the exam is a solo endeavor—integrity is critical, as any form of cheating will disqualify you from current and future attempts.

## Are you ready to certify your skills?

The exam is administered securely online through our [Training portal](https://xperience.training.kentico.com). Upon passing, you will earn your developer certificate and a mark of approval that significantly boosts your marketability and competitive edge in the industry.

Need more certainty about your readiness? The certification course offers a short sample test that will help you validate your skills. And if you are unsuccessful and pass with 64% or more, you can request an exam consultation. 

## Do you need more info about the exam?

Then read a blog post about what it's like to take the Xperience by Kentico Certified developer exam by Liam Goldfinch, Kentico MVP who [shares his experience](https://www.goldfinch.me/blog/a-guide-to-the-xperience-by-kentico-certified-developer-certification) from beta-testing the exam. Big thanks, Liam and the other testers!

Join the ranks of certified Xperience by Kentico developers. The path to becoming a recognized Xperience expert awaits.
]]>
  </BlogPostContentContentMarkdown>
  <BlogPostContentDXTopics>
    <![CDATA[[{"Identifier":"03f31ee7-6855-4b40-9ca3-08418618d0c2"},{"Identifier":"5a35a368-37fb-4fce-999f-2dca9b9c7277"},{"Identifier":"ba042c18-9429-4cf0-91a8-dabf62520a27"},{"Identifier":"378366be-601d-42b0-a719-5daee7392fb9"},{"Identifier":"32675374-2ca5-4e47-bcf9-8e3bc952ccdb"},{"Identifier":"b1318d81-f9d8-4cec-9590-23d622daf9d6"},{"Identifier":"1015b219-7365-459f-9474-0c96a842291c"},{"Identifier":"9d7f9413-3142-4f27-a6bc-fb9ec266d45f"}]]]>
  </BlogPostContentDXTopics>
  <BlogPostContentPublishedDate>2024-07-30 18:59:00Z</BlogPostContentPublishedDate>
  <BlogPostContentSourceType>markdown</BlogPostContentSourceType>
  <ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
    <GUID>84b9e9e9-b26c-4d51-91c2-aa0506cc413c</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.contentitemcommondata</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>CertifiedDeveloperExam-f25imx9t</CodeName>
      <GUID>e876a8b6-443a-4900-ae0e-2ca0bbc2e8d2</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.contentitem</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
  <ContentItemDataGUID>b7e8361f-6106-4e5c-aba3-d59a1b785ecd</ContentItemDataGUID>
</contentitemdata.kenticocommunity.blogpostcontent>