<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<contentitemdata.kenticocommunity.blogpostcontent>
  <BlogPostContentAuthor>
    <![CDATA[[{"Identifier":"2dce9183-2830-4794-ad72-edd6bd9dc5c3"}]]]>
  </BlogPostContentAuthor>
  <BlogPostContentBlogType>
    <![CDATA[[{"Identifier":"0865e8f6-2568-425e-94d8-2bf53adcdd57"}]]]>
  </BlogPostContentBlogType>
  <BlogPostContentContentMarkdown>
<![CDATA[
Over the past year, we've announced several tools that will help you migrate content and data to Xperience by Kentico solutions:

- [How to upgrade Kentico 12 to a cutting-edge DXP](https://www.kentico.com/discover/blog/how-to-upgrade-kentico-12-to-a-cutting-edge-dxp)
- [Upgrading Kentico Xperience 13 to Xperience by Kentico](https://www.kentico.com/discover/blog/upgrading-kentico-xperience-13-to-xperience-by-kentico)
- [Join Kentico with our new Universal Migration Toolkit](https://www.kentico.com/discover/blog/join-kentico-with-our-new-universal-migration-toolkit)

We even published an expert roundtable covering [what to look out for when migrating your website](https://www.kentico.com/discover/blog/what-to-look-out-for-when-migrating-your-website).

You could say, we're very interested in the topic of migrations! Well, we are interested because **you** are interested. Partners and customers have told us they are excited about Xperience by Kentico and want to start using it today. They've also told us they want to bring as much of their data and content investment with them as possible, whether they are upgrading from an earlier version of Kentico, another vendor's product, or an old, custom CMS from 15 years ago. This is why we created the tools mentioned in the articles I linked above.

Although these tools are being used to speed up time to market, they didn't have a cohesive message or clear usage guidance since they were built organically and independently over the past year.

Today, we're relaunching all of our migration tools under a new name - [the Xperience by Kentico Migration Toolkit](https://github.com/kentico/xperience-by-kentico-migration-toolkit).

The Xperience by Kentico Migration Toolkit is a _set of tools_ designed to help teams migrate content from a variety of data sources into Xperience by Kentico solutions.

These tools help automate the transfer of content and data with simple tool configuration. Each tool is provided as an open-source fully supported and documented integration on GitHub.

The Migration Toolkit, and migration support in general, is **a feature** of Xperience by Kentico that we have been investing in since April, 2022 and will continue to invest in with major enhancements to the toolkit appearing [on our public roadmap](https://roadmap.kentico.com/tabs/6-next-refreshes).

Our goal with the Migration Toolkit _is not_ to cover 100% of content and data migration into Xperience by Kentico. Instead, we want to help you significantly reduce the cost of this migration work in your projects.

By making the tools open source on GitHub, our community is free to use them out-of-the-box or customize them for their specific project needs. Kentico will continue to update the migration tools as the starting solutions and Xperience by Kentico adopt new features and capabilities so that the scope of what they can migrate equals what Xperience by Kentico can support.

[![Xperience by Kentico Migration Toolkit tool pathways to Xperience by Kentico](/getmedia/cf2dfb13-2bd2-4921-bddb-0bb56abcf710/xperience-by-kentico-migration-toolkit-embedded.webp)](/getmedia/cf2dfb13-2bd2-4921-bddb-0bb56abcf710/xperience-by-kentico-migration-toolkit-embedded.webp)

Each of the tools in the [Xperience by Kentico Migration Toolkit](https://github.com/kentico/xperience-by-kentico-migration-toolkit) are linked and described in the table below.

| Name                                                                                                   | Description                                                                                                  |
| ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ |
| [Kentico Migration Tool](https://github.com/Kentico/xperience-by-kentico-kentico-migration-tool)       | A customizable tool that migrates older **Kentico** solutions to the latest version of Xperience by Kentico. |
| [Sitecore Migration Tool](https://github.com/Kentico/xperience-by-kentico-sitecore-migration-tool)     | A customizable tool that migrates **Sitecore** solutions to Xperience by Kentico.                            |
| [Sitefinity Migration Tool](https://github.com/Kentico/xperience-by-kentico-sitefinity-migration-tool) | A customizable tool that migrates **Sitefinity** solutions to Xperience by Kentico.**                   |
| [Universal Migration Tool](https://github.com/Kentico/xperience-by-kentico-universal-migration-tool)   | Underlying technology to enable content and data imports from **any data source** into Xperience by Kentico. |

The GitHub repository for each tool now includes updated, more consistent documentation and visual diagrams showing how the tool can be use. This is especially relevant for the [Kentico Migration Tool](https://github.com/Kentico/xperience-by-kentico-kentico-migration-tool) which can migrate content from several older versions of Kentico solutions built with a variety of technologies.

:::note
**The Sitefinity Migration Tool is now live as a [Labs Limited Support](https://github.com/Kentico/.github/blob/main/SUPPORT.md#labs-limited-support) project, but will be fully launched with [the August 2024 Refresh](https://roadmap.kentico.com/c/218-sitefinity-migration-tool).
:::

]]>
  </BlogPostContentContentMarkdown>
  <BlogPostContentDXTopics>
    <![CDATA[[{"Identifier":"1a2a8dca-bfab-4c00-ac5d-898d0a08d5e4"},{"Identifier":"e3623da6-d90c-4089-9fd0-25df6c30bee8"},{"Identifier":"577d5787-5562-4e9a-8ad6-044fdfa6ac31"},{"Identifier":"239193da-cb03-4e0f-a03f-ba3f483240bf"},{"Identifier":"426073bb-93c4-4f20-a263-65bcae9ee019"},{"Identifier":"1e20bb74-10ed-46b5-956c-9ad2c5ca1fa6"},{"Identifier":"57ca3639-b27e-47f3-9fc6-8981355fa232"},{"Identifier":"b492b56d-3869-4f3e-bda5-cf8dd6588291"}]]]>
  </BlogPostContentDXTopics>
  <BlogPostContentPublishedDate>2024-07-25 18:20:00Z</BlogPostContentPublishedDate>
  <BlogPostContentSourceType>markdown</BlogPostContentSourceType>
  <ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
    <GUID>cf00b6ee-5448-435c-8b24-6d6499298a68</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.contentitemcommondata</ObjectType>
    <Parent>
      <CodeName>AnnouncingTheUpdatedXperienceByKenticoMigrationToolkit-puvp8ts7</CodeName>
      <GUID>e2da691c-2d15-405a-b95b-e1accf10d2b6</GUID>
      <ObjectType>cms.contentitem</ObjectType>
    </Parent>
  </ContentItemDataCommonDataID>
  <ContentItemDataGUID>b66710d2-a662-4ee1-ae71-d02953fb407c</ContentItemDataGUID>
</contentitemdata.kenticocommunity.blogpostcontent>